transavia.com 2017-10-24

# Privacy statement | Transavia

Transavia Airlines C.V. and Transavia France S.A.S. (hereinafter jointly referred to as ‘Transavia’) believe strongly that your personal information should be treated in a careful and safe manner. The general principle here is that you have as much control over this information as possible and that Transavia does not make your personal information available to third parties without your consent.   

## This privacy statement contains information on:

- How Transavia handles the personal information you provide to Transavia when booking a flight.

- The use of the Transavia website, which is the property of Transavia Airlines C.V.

The Transavia Airlines C.V. registered office is located in (1117 EE) Schiphol at Piet Guilonardweg 15, the Netherlands. The Transavia France S.A.S. registered office is located in (91550) Paray-Vieille-Poste at 3 allée Hélène Boucher, France.

## Processing of personal information

In order to offer our Transavia products and services, it is necessary for us to process such information as your name, address, e-mail address, phone number, travel preferences, personal interests and any information required for payment purposes. You are not required to provide this information to Transavia. However, if you do not wish to provide this information, we will not always be able to provide the requested service and/or product. 

The information is also stored and protected from improper use in accordance with the requirements that may be imposed on it. This means that, among other things, only authorised personnel can access your information and Transavia uses well-established technologies for the storage and protection of your data. 

According to the Personal Data Protection Act (WBP), Transavia Airlines has registered the methods for processing your personal data with the Dutch Data Protection Authority (Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens, AP) in The Hague. This information can be found on the AP website at [www.autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl](https://www.collegebeschermingpersoonsgegevens.nl/). According to the ‘Loi Informatique et Libertés’, Transavia France S.A.S. has registered the methods for processing your personal data with the ‘Commission Nationale de l’Informatique et des Libertés’ (CNIL) in Paris. Information on this can be found on the CNIL website at [www.cnil.fr](https://www.cnil.fr/).

## For what other purposes does Transavia process your personal information?

In addition to processing your information in order to deliver services and products, we also use the information you provide to inform you in a customised manner about the available services, products, events and news. The processing of your information also helps us develop new services and products. 

If you do not wish for us to use your information for these purposes, please let us know. We will no longer use the data for these purposes in that case. It goes without saying that you can always ask Transavia to view the information or to change or delete the information you provide. You do this using the [Complaint form](http://service-en.transavia.com/app/ask/). 

## Newsletter

You can subscribe to the Transavia newsletter. If you sign up for the newsletter, you are authorising Transavia to use your e-mail address to send the newsletter and other information, such as special offers, competitions/prize contests and surveys.

If you wish to subscribe or unsubscribe to the newsletter, you do so as follows: 

Subscribe: Transavia homepage – enter e-mail address under ‘Newsletter subscription’   
Unsubscribe: click on the ‘Unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of the Transavia newsletter

## Links

The Transavia website contains links to other websites and/or sources. Transavia assumes no responsibility and/or liability for these. This privacy statement therefore does not apply to these websites and/or sources. 

If you purchase other services when booking a flight that are provided by third parties, your information may be provided by Transavia to this third party for purposes of concluding an agreement with this third party. By selecting this service, you are authorising Transavia to share your information with this third party. Naturally, this information will only be kept and processed by this third party if you actually conclude an agreement with this party. To this end we can also share information with these third parties, for example in relation to your account, so that we can serve you fully, act on the agreement in the right way and undertake marketing activities. 

However, Transavia is not responsible for the privacy policy of these other websites, sources or third parties. We strongly recommend that you always read carefully through the privacy policies of other websites and/or sources and/or third parties.

## Processing of personal information required by authorities 

Transavia is increasingly obliged to provide various authorities in countries around the world – e.g. customs, immigration- and security services – in advance with the personal and travel details of its passengers. These may include API (Advance Passenger Information, primarily passport and travel information) and PNR (Passenger Name Record, primarily travel and booking information) details. In certain cases, Transavia is also required to photocopy the passports of its passengers before departure. This is necessary for the fulfillment of the contract of carriage and for reasons of safety in particular. Authorities may require this data for example for immigration purposes and in order to prevent and control possible terrorism and serious crime. We wish to emphasize that the authorities concerned have assured us that your reservation details will only be used for safety purposes and can only be accessed by authorized personnel. 

Regarding flights operated by Transavia France S.A.S – flights which have a flight number starting with ‘TO’, the following applies:

In accordance with the Data Protection Law No. 78-18 of 6 January 1978 relating to computers, files and privacy, and Article L. 232-7 of the French Code of Homeland Security, your API and PNR data may be transmitted to the “Passenger Information Unit”. The "Passenger Information Unit" (PIU) is a service of the French administration that brings together the various authorities responsible for the prevention and fight against terrorism and serious crime and to prevent the undermining of fundamental interests of the French Nation.

**What kind of data are transmitted?**

  * API (Advance Passenger information): Some of your flight data and your travel document data are transmitted to the Passenger Information Unit.
  * PNR (Passenger Name Record): Some of your flight and booking data are transmitted to the Passenger Information Unit 

**How do I know if it concerns my flight and my data is transmitted?**

  * For all flights operated by Transavia France S.A.S. from France to a non-EU country and all flights operated by Transavia France S.A.S. from a non EU-Country to France, API and PNR data are transmitted to the PIU. 
  * API: If it concerns your flight, you will be asked to communicate some of your travel document data during the check-in (online or at the airport). 
  * PNR: If it concerns your flight, some of your PNR data are automatically transmitted by Transavia France to PIU.

## No-fly list

To maintain and manage the proper order and safety of and during flights, Transavia has a No-fly list. This list contains the names of passengers who have disrupted safety, good order and discipline on board and/or on the ground to such an extent that they may not be flown on board a Transavia flight for a limited period of time – or under conditions to be determined by Transavia. The persons concerned are informed in writing by Transavia about their placement on this list and the applicable time period.

## Changes

This privacy statement pertains to the use of your personal information by Transavia and the possibilities of this website. Any adaptations and/or changes to this website may lead to changes in this privacy statement. It is therefore advisable to read through this privacy statement on a regular basis.  
After all, Transavia will only use the information provided in accordance with this privacy statement and for the purpose for which this information was collected. If Transavia decides to use personally identifiable information in a manner other than prescribed in the privacy statement, Transavia must inform the persons concerned of this by e-mail. You will then have the choice as to whether or not to authorise this use. 

## Cookies

When visiting the website, the Transavia web server automatically stores your IP address. Your IP address is a number that makes it possible for computers in the network to identify your computer, so that information (such as web pages) can be sent to your computer. Transavia uses cookies when offering its services. A cookie is a compact piece of information that is stored on your computer. When visiting the Transavia website, this cookie is created and read. For more information on cookies, read the [Transavia cookie policy](https://www.transavia.com/en-EU/the-small-print/cookie-policy/).

## Questions

If you have any questions or complaints on the protection of your personal data by Transavia, please contact us via the [Transavia Call Centre](https://www.transavia.com/en-EU/service/customer-service/).

Transavia Airlines C.V.  
Transavia France S.A.S.

August 2016
